# ANDREY LYAMKIN

Montreal, QC | andrew.lyamkin@gmail.com | https://lyamkin.github.io/portfolio-web/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreylyamkin/

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented Web-developer with organized nature, customer-focused mindset, and good critical thinking skills. Talented troubleshooter, and problem solver. Familiar with code review, performance evaluation and project coordination tasks.

1+ years of professional programming experience with Java, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, HTML, CSS, ORACLE DB, MySQL DB.

6+ years of professional experience in Computer networks LAN, Wireless LAN. Advanced knowledge in TCP/IP computer networks and network security.

#### **SKILLS**

- Java, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, GitHub
- Oracle DB, SQL, PL/SQL
- Linux, CLI, TCP/IP, Routing and Switching
- Blockchain concepts

# **WORK HISTORY**

# **Data center Operator,** 12/2017 to 03/2020

#### Cryptologic Inc. – Montreal, QC

- Participated in developing special monitoring system software.
- Contributed to and led projects in the deployment, maintenance, and support of current and new data center infrastructure.
- Led complex troubleshooting and resolved critical or escalated technical issues over a population of affected equipment.
- Helped test and troubleshoot new complex hardware components and designs.
- Configured and troubleshoot OS-related issues on equipment.
- Used diagnostic tools to identify hardware failures and replace non-functional components.
- Installed equipment for data communications networks including cabling, routers, switches.

**Independent Contractor,** 09/2016 to 11/2017

Self-employed – Winnipeg, MB

# ANDREY LYAMKIN

Montreal, QC | andrew.lyamkin@gmail.com | https://lyamkin.github.io/portfolio-web/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreylyamkin/

#### **Data center Analyst,** 11/2011 to 06/2016

# Cellular Network "Motiv", GSM/LTE operator – Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Collaborated with team in development of Web User interface for displaying computer network statistics. It allowed to analyze data two times faster and more efficient in compare with old approach.
- Monitored and analyzed wireless system performance, such as network traffic, security and capacity.
- Produced monthly Wireless network Health reports using advanced Excel spreadsheet functions.
- Developed database objects, including tables, views and materialized views using SQL.

### Computer Network Technician, 04/2010 to 11/2011

# Cellular Network "Motiv", GSM/LTE operator – Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Traveled to remote office locations to install nodes and implement client software rollouts.
- Installed equipment for data communications networks including cabling, wireless routers and telephone systems.

# **EDUCATION**

Web and Database Programming, 05/2020

Vanier College - Montreal, QC

Java development, 09/2017

ComIT - Winnipeg, MB

Bachelor's: Information Systems and Technologies, 07/2008

Ural State Mining University – Yekaterinburg, Russia

# **ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS**

Literature, travel, Self-education